A Guide to the James Hugo Johnston, Jr. Papers 1876-1962
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
James Hugo Johnston, Jr. Papers 1891-1974
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1876-1962
2000 items
Business and personal correspondence of the son of the president of Virginia State University. James Hugo Johnston Jr., served as professor of history, Dean of the School of Arts and Sciences and Vice President of Virginia State University. He authored many articles on history and authored Race Relations in Virginia and Miscegenation in the South.
James Hugo Johnston, Jr.
Administrative Information
Access
No restrictions on access.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mr. James Hugo Johnston Jr., was born on May 10,1891 on the campus of Virginia State University in the village of Ettrick, Virginia. James Hugo Johnston Jr, was the son of James Hugo and Anna Johnston Sr. James Hugo Johnston Jr. followed in the footsteps of his father by serving on the faculty of Virginia State University; which his father James Hugo Johnston Sr., had served as the Universities second president. James Hugo Johnston Jr. married Bessie Adkins on September 24,1922 and fathered one son James Hugo Johnston III.
Mr. James Hugo Johnston Jr., studied in 1905-09 at Virginia State University until he was forced to finish his education at Virginia Union University because of the abolishment of the college program at Virginia State University. Mr. Johnston later received his B.A in 1913 from Virginia Union University; and later went on to the University of Chicago where he received his M.A in 1925 and his Ph.D. in 1937.
Mr. Johnston served as a member of the Virginia State University faculty since 1914-1961. He served as professor of history 1914 to 1920; Dean of the college 1929-1949 and 1950-1957; Acting president 1949- 1950; and Vice president 1943 ? June 30,1961.
Mr. Johnston was an aspiring man who's correspondence includes letters from William E. Dodd, Will Alexander, Luther Foster, and most influential Dr. Carter G. Woodson. The letters talk about the many problems James Hugo Johnston Jr. went through on his journey to publish his doctoral dissertation on race relations in the south "1776-1860."
James Hugo Johnston's many organizational memberships included; the Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools (President 1942), the American Historical association, the Virginia State University Alumni Association (treasurer) the Virginia Teachers Association, and the American Teachers Association.
James Hugo Johnston Jr., was the author of Race Relations in the South 1776-1860 and numerous Articles.
James Hugo Johnston Jr., retired from Virginia State University on July 1,1961. He later continued to work on the history of Virginia State University until he died in 1974.
Scope and Content Information
James Hugo Johnston Jr., son of the second president of Virginia State University was one of the first African Americans to receive the Ph.D. in History. James Hugo Johnston Jr., was a professor of history and government at Virginia State University from 1914 until 1961. During this time he served as Dean, Vice president and Acting president of the University.
His correspondence reflects his long career as a scholar and as well as one of the primary administrators of the University. There are quite a few interesting letters with Carter. G. Woodson regarding the publication of his Doctoral dissertation.
In the Johnston papers are correspondence from the Julius Rosenwald and Guggenheim foundations, these were organizations that James Hugo Johnston requested funds for to aid him in his Ph.D. degree. Along Mr. Johnston's process he also received letters from the Fellowship of the Social Science research Council, The university of Chicago, The general education Board, Julius Rosenwald foundation and the Guggenheim foundation.
Series Description
Series I. Correspondence The Correspondence discusses a wide range of topics. Included in this series are some correspondence from Carter G. Woodson, and other notable colleagues of James Hugo Johnston Jr.
Series II. Virginia State University National Alumni Association This series reflects Johnston's position of treasurer of the National Alumni Association. Included are ledgers, correspondence, executive committee notes, treasurers reports, printed programs and a listing of Virginia State University Alumni Association events and projects from 1931 until the 1960's.
Series III. Literary Documents used for the history of Virginia State University from 1882-1914. Which was commissioned by the school. This was never published.
Series IV. Research Research notes used by Johnston for his dissertation and history of Virginia State University.
Series V. Photographs Photograph's of family and non-family members. The photos are grouped in two sub series, which include pictures of the Johnston family, and non-family member photos.
Series VI. Printed Degrees of James Hugo Johnston Jr., and other family members from Virginia State University, Virginia Union University, Shaw University and the University of Chicago. Also are copies of two Newspapers from Danville, Virginia. One of them, is The Mirror, which was African American.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - General
    - Correspondence 1927,1929 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Correspondence 1930 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Correspondence 1931 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Correspondence 1932 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Correspondence 1933 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Correspondence 1934 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Correspondence 1935 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Correspondence 1936 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Correspondence 1937 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Correspondence 1938 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Correspondence 1940 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Correspondence 1941 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Correspondence 1942 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - Correspondence 1943 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Correspondence 1944 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Corrrespondence 1946 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Correspondence 1947-48 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Correspondence 1949 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - Corrrespondence 1950 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Correspondence 1951 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Correspondence 1952 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Correspondence 1953 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Correspondence 1954 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - Correspondence 1955 (Box-folder 1:24)
    - Correspondence 1956 (Box-folder 1:25)
    - Correspondence 1957 (Box-folder 1:26)
    - Correspondence 1958 (Box-folder 1:27)
    - Correspondence 1959 (Box-folder 1:28)
    - Correspondence 1960 (Box-folder 1:29)
    - Correspondence 1961 (Box-folder 1:30)
    - Correspondence 1962 (Box-folder 1:31)
    - Correspondence N.D. (Box-folder 1:32)
  - The A.S.A.L.H.
    - The A.S.N.L.H. Correspondence 1927,1930 (Box-folder 1:33)
    - The A.S.N.L.H. Correspondence 1931 (Box-folder 1:34)
    - The A.S.N.L.H. Correspondence 1932 (Box-folder 1:35)
    - The A.S.N.L.H. Correspondence 1933,1937 (Box-folder 1:36)
    - The A.S.N.L.H. Correspondence 1938,1939 (Box-folder 1:37)
    - The A.S.N.L.H. Correspondence 1950,1963 (Box-folder 1:38)
  - Correspondences with V.S.U
    - Correspondence History of V.S.U 1958 - 63 (Box-folder 1:39)
  - UMASS Press
    - Johnston & UMASS Correspondence 1968 - 1970 (Box-folder 1:40)
- VSU National Alumni Association
  - Ledgers
    - Correspondence 1916 - 1938 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Correspondence 1927 - 1952 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Correspondence 1951 - 1954 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Correspondence 1952 - 1954 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Alumni Correspondence 1930-1965
    - Alumni Correspondence 1930-1931 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1932 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1934 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1936 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1937 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1938 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1939 (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1940 (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1941 (Box-folder 3:9)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1942 (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1943,1946 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1947 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1948 (Box-folder 3:13)
    - Alumni Correspondence Feb.- Jul. 1949 (Box-folder 3:14)
    - Alumni Correspondence Aug. - Dec. 1949 (Box-folder 3:15)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1950 (Box-folder 3:16)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1951 - 1952 (Box-folder 3:17)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1954 - 1955 (Box-folder 3:18)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1957 (Box-folder 3:19)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1958 (Box-folder 3:20)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1959 (Box-folder 3:21)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1961 (Box-folder 3:22)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1962 (Box-folder 3:23)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1963 (Box-folder 3:24)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1964 (Box-folder 3:25)
    - Alumni Correspondence 1965 (Box-folder 3:26)
  - Ex-Committee, Minutes 1930 - 1940
    - Ex - Committee Minutes 1936 - 1940 (Box-folder 3:27)
    - Alumni Minutes 1943 (Box-folder 3:28A)
    - Alumni Minutes 1954 (Box-folder 3:28B)
    - Alumni Minutes 1959 (Box-folder 3:28C)
    - Alumni Minutes 1960 (Box-folder 3:28D)
    - Alumni Minutes 1964 (Box-folder 3:28E)
    - Alumni Minutes 1965 (Box-folder 3:28F)
  - Ex - Secretary Reports 1949 - 1955
    - Ex - Secretary Reports 1949 (Box-folder 3:29)
    - Ex - Secretary Reports 1950 (Box-folder 3:30)
    - Ex - Secretary Reports 1951 (Box-folder 3:31)
    - Ex - Secretary Reports 1952 (Box-folder 3:32)
    - Ex - Secretary Reports 1953 (Box-folder 3:33)
    - Ex - Secretary Reports 1954 (Box-folder 3:34)
    - Ex - Secretary Reports 1955 (Box-folder 3:35)
  - The Treasurer Reports 1938 - 1966
    - Expense Reports 1942 (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Treasurer Reports 1934 - 1938 (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Treasurer Reports 1938 - 1940 (Box-folder 4:3)
    - Treasurer Reports 1936 - 1938 (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Treasurer Reports 1939 - 1940 (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Treasurer Reports 1940 - 1942 (Box-folder 4:6)
    - Treasurer Reports 1942 - 1944 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Treasurer Reports 1944 - 1946 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Treasurer Reports 1946 - 1948 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - Treasurer Reports Mar. - May. 1949 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Treasurer Reports May 1949 (Box-folder 4:11)
    - Treasurer Reports 1950 (Box-folder 4:12)
    - Treasurer Reports 1951 (Box-folder 4:13)
    - Treasurer Reports 1952 (Box-folder 4:14)
    - Treasurer Reports 1953 (Box-folder 4:15)
    - Treasurer Reports 1954 (Box-folder 4:16)
    - Treasurer Reports 1955 (Box-folder 4:17)
    - Treasurer Reports 1956 (Box-folder 4:18)
    - Treasurer Reports 1957 (Box-folder 4:19)
    - Treasurer Reports 1958 (Box-folder 4:20)
    - Treasurer Reports 1959 (Box-folder 4:21)
    - Treasurer Reports 1960 (Box-folder 4:22)
    - Treasurer Reports 1965 (Box-folder 4:23)
    - Treasurer Reports 1966 (Box-folder 4:24)
  - Chapter Reports 1917 - 1953
    - Chapter Reports 1917 (Box-folder 4:25)
    - Chapter Reports 1938 (Box-folder 4:26)
    - Chapter Reports 1940 (Box-folder 4:27)
    - Chapter Reports 1940 (Box-folder 4:28)
    - Chapter Reports 1942 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Chapter Reports 1945 (Box-folder 5:2)
    - Chapter Reports 1946 (Box-folder 5:3)
    - Chapter Reports 1947 (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Chapter Reports 1948 (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Chapter Reports 1949 (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Chapter Reports 1950 (Box-folder 5:7)
    - Chapter Reports 1951 (Box-folder 5:8)
    - Chapter Reports 1952-1953 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - Printed Programs
    - 1910,22,51,52,54 (Box-folder 5:10)
    - Printed Programs 1936, 40, 48 (Box-folder 5:11)
    - Printed Programs 1940, 64 (Box-folder 5:12)
    - Printed Programs 1948, 64 (Box-folder 5:13)
    - Printed Programs 1938 (Box-folder 5:14)
  - Alumni Activities
    - Virginia Hall Memorial 1937 (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Virginia Hall Memorial 1938 (Box-folder 5:16)
    - John M Gandy Bust 1940 (Box-folder 5:17)
    - Band Fund 1938, 1950 (Box-folder 5:18)
    - Athletic Association 1940, 41, 46 (Box-folder 5:19)
    - Financial Statement 1953 (Box-folder 5:20)
    - Camilla Williams 1946, 50, 64, 72 (Box-folder 5:21)
    - Alumni-O-Grams 1941 (Box-folder 5:22)
    - Class of 1939 1939 (Box-folder 5:23)
    - Organ Fund 1940, 41 (Box-folder 5:24)
    - Induction of Graduates 1941 (Box-folder 5:25)
    - Gifts of the College 1940, 1942 (Box-folder 5:26)
    - News Release 1946 (Box-folder 5:27)
    - Alumni Survey 1932 (Box-folder 5:28)
    - Alumni House 1943, 49 (Box-folder 5:29)
    - Alumni House 1950, 51, 53 (Box-folder 5:30)
    - Alumni House 1959 (July - September) (Box-folder 5:31)
    - Alumni House 1959 (Oct.) (Box-folder 5:32)
    - Alumni House 1959 (Dec.) (Box-folder 5:33)
    - Alumni House 1960 (Box-folder 5:34)
    - Alumni House 1961 (Box-folder 5:35)
    - Telegrams 1949 (Box-folder 5:36)
    - Alumni Minutes 1950 (Box-folder 5:37)
    - Alumni House List 1950, 51 (Box-folder 5:38)
    - Correspondence Presidents Office 1956 (Box-folder 5:39)
    - Presidential Appointment 1942 (Box-folder 5:40)
    - Alumni Roster (Box-folder 5:41)
    - List of Graduates 1943 (Box-folder 5:42)
- Literary
  - Published
    - A new Interpretation of the Domestic Slave System (Box-folder 6:43)
    - Graduates of Northern High Schools as students at a Southern Negro College (Box-folder 6:44)
    - The Spread of Mohammedanism in Africa (Box-folder 6:45)
    - A Great Loyalty (Box-folder 6:46)
    - The Mohammedan slave Trade (Box-folder 6:47)
    - The preparation of pius for the papacy (Box-folder 6:48)
  - Unpublished History of Virginia State College
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 1 Version 1 (Box-folder 7:1)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 1 Version 2 (Box-folder 7:2)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 2 Version 1 (Box-folder 7:3)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 2 Version 2 (Box-folder 7:4)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 3 (Box-folder 7:5)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 3 C.C (Box-folder 7:6)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 4 (Box-folder 7:7)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 4 C.C (Box-folder 7:8)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 5 (Box-folder 7:9)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 5 C.C (Box-folder 7:10)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 6 (Box-folder 7:11)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 6 C.C (Box-folder 7:12)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 7 John Mercer Langston (Box-folder 7:13)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 7 C.C John Mercer Langston (Box-folder 7:14)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 8 Version 1 Student Life (Box-folder 7:15)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 8 Version 2 (Box-folder 7:16)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 9 Version 1 The Faculty and Staff (Box-folder 7:17)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 9 Version 2 (Box-folder 7:18)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 10 Version 1 After the Convention 1900 (Box-folder 7:19)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 10 Version 2 (Box-folder 7:20)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 8 Version 11 same as 10 2.1 After the convention 1901 - 1902 (Box-folder 7:21)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 12 Version 1 1905 - 1914 (Box-folder 7:22)
    - History of V.S.C. Chapter 12 C.C 1905 - 1914 (Box-folder 7:23)
- Research
  - Research Notes
    - History of V.N. & C.I. James Storum 1855 - 1885 (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Virginia State College, James H. Johnston, Jr. (Box-folder 8:2)
    - The History of V.N. & I.I., James H. Johnston, Jr. 1926 (Box-folder 8:3)
    - History of V.N. & I.I. (Tables) 1883 (Box-folder 8:4)
    - A Brief Account of V.N. & I.I., Sylvia Coleman 1883 - 1914 (A) (Box-folder 8:5)
    - A Brief Account of V.N. & I.I., Sylvia Coleman 1883 - 1914 (B) (Box-folder 8:6)
    - An Act to Incorporate V.N. & C.I. 1881-1882 (Box-folder 8:7)
    - President's Notebook (Extracts) 1884 - 1891 (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Students Rules (Extracts) 1892 - 1893 (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Summer Normals 1885 (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Petition of Students 1902 (Box-folder 8:11)
    - How our Graduates are Employed 1905 (Box-folder 8:12)
    - Distribution of Alumni 1936 (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Bagnall, Lillian Sophronia (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Buchanan, John Lee (Box-folder 8:15)
    - This is Your Life, Edna M. Colson (Box-folder 8:16)
    - Colson, James Major (Box-folder 8:17)
    - Daniel, Charles James 1888 - 1916 (Box-folder 8:18)
    - Davis, Jackson 1882 - 1947 (Box-folder 8:19)
    - Franklin, Charles Sumner (Box-folder 8:20)
    - Hayden, Mrs. Della (Box-folder 8:21)
    - Jackson, Luther P. (Box-folder 8:22)
    - Johnston, Sr., James H. (Box-folder 8:23)
    - Forgotten Prophet The Life of John Mercer Langston William F. Cheek III (Box-folder 8:24)
    - John M. Langston, by Harriett A. Little 1887 - 1888 (Box-folder 8:25)
    - Lindsay, Miss Anna L (Box-folder 8:26 (A))
    - Mann, albert Russell 1880 - 1947 (Box-folder 8:26 (B))
    - Mahone, William of Virginia (Box-folder 8:27)
    - Mitchell, Samuel Chiles (Box-folder 8:28)
    - Owens, George Washington (Box-folder 8:29)
    - Rogers, William A. (Box-folder 8:30)
    - Southall, James Cooke (Box-folder 8:31)
    - Storum, James (Box-folder 8:32)
    - Vawter, C.E. (Materials) (Box-folder 8:33)
    - Wynn, Alexander (Box-folder 8:34)
    - Remarks on Portrait of Negro Members of VA Leg 1887 (Folder 8:35)
    - Remarks of James A. Porter, painting of R.P. Daniel 1953 (Box-folder 8:36)
    - Presentation of Portraits of Presidents at V.S.C. 1953 (Box-folder 8:37)
    - Williams, Henry Scrapbook Index (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Williams, Henry Scrapbook (Box-folder 9:2)
    - Williams, Henry Scrapbook (120 - 188) (Box-folder 9:3)
    - Williams, Henry Scrapbook (1- 118) (Box-folder 9:4)
    - Williams, Henry Scrapbook Scrapbook Miscellaneous Materials (Box-folder 9:5)
    - Williams, Henry Scrapbook (Box-folder 9:6)
    - V.S.C. Board of Visitors Minute Book (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Virginia School Reports 1882 - 1892 (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Research Notes V.S.U. (Speeches, Copies)
    - Are we Always Right in Obeying the Dictates of our Conscience 1878 (Box-folder 10:1)
    - Concerning Revival of 1878 (Box-folder 10:2)
    - The importance of Morals In Education 1884 (Folder 10:3)
    - The Retrospect 1884 (Box-folder 10:4)
    - The Duty We Owe Posterity 1885 (Box-folder 10:5)
    - The True Status of Negro Masonry in America 1887 (Box-folder 10:6)
    - An Unsolved Problem 1889 (Box-folder 10:7)
    - The Model Teacher 1889 (Box-folder 10:8)
    - The End of Education 1890 (Box-folder 10:9)
    - Character Essential to True Manhood 1893 - 1894 (Box-folder 10:10)
    - Some of Our Conceits 1895 (Box-folder 10:11)
    - The American Home 1897 (Box-folder 10:12)
    - Presiding Bishop and Members of the Bishop Confrence 1898 (Box-folder 10:13)
    - Manliness 1898 (Box-folder 10:14)
    - The American Home 1899 (Box-folder 10:15)
    - Our Duty to Attempt the Impossible 1901 (Box-folder 10:16)
    - Our Educational Status (Box-folder 10:17)
    - The Pyramids (Box-folder 10:18)
    - To The first Baptist Church, Assembled (Box-folder 10:19)
    - The Public Schools (Box-folder 10:20)
    - The Sunday School Teacher (Box-folder 10:21)
    - Parental Obedience (Box-folder 10:22)
    - Patriotism (Box-folder 10:23)
    - Alexander the Great (Box-folder 10:24)
    - The Cause of Declining Health Among School Children (Box-folder 10:25)
    - The Woodville School (Box-folder 10:26)
    - Our Prepatory Schools and Colleges Their Relation to the Professions (Box-folder 10:27)
    - Heat (Box-folder 10:28)
    - Kindness (Box-folder 10:29)
    - Misconceptions of The Nature and Purpose of Education (Box-folder 10:30)
    - Lincoln (Box-folder 10:31)
  - Dissertation Notes
    - Copies of Petitions Index (Box-folder 11:1)
    - Copies of Petitions (A) (Box-folder 11:2)
    - Copies of Petitions (B) (Box-folder 11:3)
    - Copies of Petitions (C) (Box-folder 11:4)
    - Copies of Petitions D (Box-folder 11:5)
    - Copies of Petitions (E) (Box-folder 11:6)
    - Copies of Petitions (F) (Box-folder 11:7)
    - Copies of Petitions (G) (Box-folder 11:8)
    - Copies of Petitions (H) (Box-folder 11:9)
    - Copies of Petitions (I) (Box-folder 11:10)
    - Copies of Petitions (J) (Box-folder 11:11)
    - Copies of Petitions (K) (Box-folder 11:12)
    - Copies of Petitions (L) (Box-folder 11:13)
    - Copies of Petitions (M) (Box-folder 11:14)
    - Copies of Petitions (N) (Box-folder 11:15)
    - Copies of Petitions (P) (Box-folder 11:16)
    - Copies of Petitions (R) (Box-folder 11:17)
    - Copies of Petitions (S) (Box-folder 11:18)
    - Copies of Petitions (T) (Box-folder 11:19)
    - Copies of Petitions (U-V) (Box-folder 11:20)
    - Copies of Petitions (W) (Box-folder 11:21)
    - Copies of Petitions (X,Y,Z) (Box-folder 11:22)
    - Copies of Petitions UN-Classified (Box-folder 11:23)
- Johnston Papers-Photographs
  - Family
    - James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:1)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:2)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:3)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:4)
    - Family Group Picture (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Family Group Picture (Box-folder 12:6)
    - Family Group Picture (Box-folder 12:7)
    - Lowell Johnston (Box-folder 12:8)
    - Virginus Johnston (Box-folder 12:9)
    - Virginus Johnston (Box-folder 12:10)
    - Virginus Johnston (Box-folder 12:11)
    - Virginus Johnstons Graduation (Box-folder 12:12)
    - Dorothy Johnston (Box-folder 12:13)
    - Dorothy Johnston (Box-folder 12:14)
    - Dorothy Johnston (Box-folder 12:15)
    - Dorothy Johnston (Box-folder 12:16)
    - Dorothy Johnston (Box-folder 12:17)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Jr. (Box-folder 12:18)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Jr. (Box-folder 12:19)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Jr. (Box-folder 12:20)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Jr. (Box-folder 12:21)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Jr. (Box-folder 12:22)
    - Nannie Johnston (Box-folder 12:23)
    - Lowell Johnston (Box-folder 12:24)
    - Mrs. James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:25)
    - Mrs. James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:26)
    - Mrs. James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:27)
    - Mrs. James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:28)
    - Mrs. James Hugo Johnston, Sr. (Box-folder 12:29)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Jr. Graduation (Box-folder 12:30)
  - Non Family Photo's
    - Alma (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Inc. (Box-folder 13:2)
    - Alpha Phi Alpha Faculty Members (Box-folder 13:3)
    - Banquet (Box-folder 13:4)
    - William Thomas Carter (Box-folder 13:5)
    - Blanche Daniel (Box-folder 13:6)
    - Mrs. Robert P. Daniel and President Tucker View Thee Memorial to Dr. Daniel 1968 (Box-folder 13:7)
    - Dean and Registrars Confrence 1954-55 (Box-folder 13:8)
    - Unidentified Confrence (Box-folder 13:9)
    - Faculty Reception 1954 (Box-folder 13:10)
    - Faculty and Staff members 1956 (Box-folder 13:11)
    - Footbal V.S.U. Early (Box-folder 13:12)
    - Flyer-Colored normal and Collegiate Institute (Box-folder 13:13)
    - Luther H. Foster (Box-folder 13:14)
    - Founders Day 1949 (Box-folder 13:15)
    - Founders Day 1951 (Box-folder 13:16)
    - Founders Day No Date (Box-folder 13:17)
    - Founders Day 1943 (Box-folder 13:18)
    - Homecoming No Date (Box-folder 13:19)
    - F. Nathaniel Gatlin (Box-folder 13:20)
    - Harry Johnson and Wife (Box-folder 13:21)
    - Unveiling of Johnston portrait by, Borican (Box-folder 13:22)
    - James Hugo Johnston, Jr. and Campus Queens (Box-folder 13:23)
    - Johnston Confrence 1936 (Box-folder 13:24)
    - Johnston, Jr. and Friends (Box-folder 13:25)
    - Johnston and Friends (Box-folder 13:26)
    - Johnston at Virginia Union University (Box-folder 13:27)
    - Johnston Group Virginia Union University (Box-folder 13:28)
    - Anna Laura Lindsey (Box-folder 13:29)
    - Retiring Staff Members (Box-folder 13:30)
    - R.O.T.C. Ball 1950 (Box-folder 13:31)